## AUDIO ENGINEER INTERNSHIP

Professional Summary

Studio experience through a one and a half year internship. Excellent communication skills. Experienced in recording, mixing, and editing sound. Experienced in maintaining audio equipment. Deep knowledge of sound reinforcement, studio, and mixers. Excellent aural skills. Quick to problem solve and make informed decisions. Skilled team worker. Advanced computer skills in Pro Tools. Motivated audio engineer with solid experience managing many levels of large scale projects, including budgeting and administration communication.

Skills

Project Management
Self-Motivated
Strong Verbal Communication
Conflict Resolution

Extremely Organized
Process Oriented
Team Leadership

Work History

Audio Engineer Internship 01/2014 to Current Live Nation Entertainment Inc – Hartford , CT

- Involved with the Audio Engineer internship for three semesters with this company.
- Roughly 22 hours per week at the studio, while enrolled as a full time student.
- Managed and operated audio equipment, adjust audio equipment for customer needs, mix and edit audio, established an in depth understanding of ProTools.
- Obtained a high level of communication skills.
- Worked as a production assistant to produce albums with artists such as Remedy Drive, Charlie Leftridge, and The Silver Pages

## Assistant Studio Designer 09/2014 to Current

Doane Studio IT â€" City, STATE

- Researched quality equipment and software for setting up a professional studio while on a restricted budget.
- Responsible for creating a layout and floor plan for maximum engineering efficiency.
- Responsible for installing equipment and educating the staff and students on using the studio.
- Created video/audio tutorials to educate future users with basic to advanced skills necessary in the studio and engineering process.

## Sound Engineer 08/2013 to 05/2014

Jazz Unlimited Live Doane College â€" City, STATE

- Responsible for mixing live sound for the jazz ensemble in rehearsal, concerts, and tours around the state of Nebraska.
- Managed audio equipment
- Responsible for sound checks, equipment placement, and volume and quality control

## Education

Bachelor Degree of Music: Music General Emphasis 2015 Doane College - City, State General Emphasis Bachelor of Arts: Business Administration 2015 Doane College - City, State Business Administration Skills

Audio, basic, budget, communication skills, edit, Engineer, layout, next, ProTools, quality, requirement, Sound, video